Guide to the Edward J Wormley and Edward Crouse Papers,1831-1997 (bulk 1907-1997).
Wormley, Edward J and Edward Crouse Papers, 1831-1997 (bulk 1907-1997)
- Series III. Edward J Wormley Professional Records
  - Subseries IIIA. Business Records
    - Dunbar Furniture Company
      - General, 1940-1981 (Box 7, Folder 30-35)
      - Agreements, contracts, and related correspondence, 1942-1948, 1954, 1956-1959, 1965-1968, undated (Box 14, Folder 36-40)
      - Garfunkel, Harold, circa 1977 (Box 7, Folder 36)
      - Neiderhauser, Homer, 1956-1973 (Box 7, Folder 37)
      - News clippings, circa 1937-1984 (Box 7, Folder 38)
      - Sprunger, Harold, 1965-1970 (Box 7, Folder 39)
      - Sprunger, Roger, 1969-1982 (Box 7, Folder 40)
      - Thurston, Gilbert, circa 1970-1987 (Box 7, Folder 41)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - Edward Wormley and Associates
      - Business certificate, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 42)
      - Clients
        - Design Thai/Dora Sanders, 1961-April 1966 (Box 7, Folder 42)
        - Design Thai/Dora Sanders, May-August 1966 (Box 7, Folder 43)
        - Design Thai/Dora Sanders, September 1966-1968 (Box 7, Folder 44)
        - Design Thai/Dora Sanders; Floor Plans, November 1966 (Box 14, Folder 43)
        - Design Thai/Dora Sanders, undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
        - Fischer, Molly and John, 1962-1966 (Box 7, Folder 46)
        - Fischer, Molly and John, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 47)
        - Fischer, Molly and John; Floor Plans, undated (Box 7, Folder 48)
        - Fischer, Molly and John; Miscellaneous, undated (Box 7, Folder 49)
        - Fischer, Molly and John; Miscellaneous, undated (Box 7, Folder 50)
        - Frankel, David, June-December 1965 (Box 7, Folder 51)
        - Frankel, David, circa 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 52)
        - Garfunkel, Harold and Florence, 1962-1966 (Box 7, Folder 53)
        - Garfunkel, Harold and Florence, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 54)
        - Garfunkel, Harold and Florence, undated (Box 7, Folder 55)
        - Graves, Austin, May-June 1967 (Box 7, Folder 56)
        - Janeway, Elizabeth and Eliot, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 44-47)
        - Janeway, Elizabeth and Eliot; Floor Plans, March 1967 (Box 14, Folder 48)
        - Mazer, Helen and William, 1963-1966, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 49)
        - Nassau, Lillian, October 1964-February 1965 (Box 7, Folder 57)
        - Nassau, Lillian, March-May 1965 (Box 7, Folder 58)
        - Nassau, Lillian, June-August 1965 (Box 7, Folder 59)
        - Nassau, Lillian, September 1965-June 1966 (Box 7, Folder 60)
        - Nassau, Lillian; Floor Plans, December 1964 (Box 7, Folder 61)
        - Nassau, Lillian; Miscellaneous, undated (Box 7, Folder 62)
        - Schwartz, Doris and Ralph, 1963-October 1964 (Box 8, Folder 1)
        - Schwartz, Doris and Ralph, November-December 1964 (Box 14, Folder 50)
        - Schwartz, Doris and Ralph, January-March 1965 (Box 8, Folder 2)
        - Schwartz, Doris and Ralph, April-May 1965 (Box 14, Folder 51)
        - Schwartz, Doris and Ralph, June-July 1965 (Box 8, Folder 3)
        - Schwartz, Doris and Ralph, August-December 1965 (Box 8, Folder 4)
        - Schwartz, Doris and Ralph, January-April 1966 (Box 8, Folder 5)
        - Schwartz, Doris and Ralph, May 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 6)
        - Schwartz, Doris and Ralph; Floor Plans, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 7)
        - Schwartz, Doris and Ralph; Miscellaneous, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Employees
        - General, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 9)
        - Easton, David, circa 1963-1976 (Box 8, Folder 10)
        - Thaxter, Helen, 1959-1966, 1969-1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 1-6)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Subseries IIIB. Subject Files
    - Akbar, Mohhamed, and Noormohd Sultani, 1983-1985 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - American Craft Council, 1970-1991 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - American Federation of Arts, 1968-1969, 1985-1987 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - American Institute of Interior Designers, 1951, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - American Society of Interior Designers, 1978-1982 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - American Society of Interior Designers film reel, undated (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Arthur H. Lee and Sons, Ltd., 1938 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Auerbach, Alfred, 1963-1972 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Berkey and Gay Furniture Corporation, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Brill, Arthur, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Certificates of Merit and Membership, circa 1956-1960 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Cooper-Hewitt Museum, circa 1970-1980 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Cooper-Hewitt Museum; Charles A. Whitney Memorial, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - David A. Hanks and Associates, circa 1981-1985 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Denmark Colleagues, 1955-1991 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Denver Dry Goods Company Homefurnishing Style Revue, April 1937 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Denver Dry Goods Company Homefurnishing Style Revue, June 1937 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Eames, Ray, circa 1958 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Fifty/50, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Girard, Alexander, circa 1963-1966 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Gores, Landis/House for All Seasons, circa 1975 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Halpert, Edith, circa 1965-1970 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Industrial Designers Society of America, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Interior Design in the 20th Century TS; Introduction-Chapter 4 circa 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Interior Design in the 20th Century TS; Chapters 5-6, circa 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Interior Design in the 20th Century TS; Chapters 7-10, circa 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Interior Design in the 20th Century TS; Miscellaneous, circa 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - International Graphic Arts Society, 1971-1978 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Irish Georgian Society/Desmond Guinness, 1964-1974 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Kaufmann, Edgar (Jr.), 1947-1955, 1965-1979, undated (Box 8, Folder 35-37)
    - Kaufmann, Edgar (Jr.), 1962-1964 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Larsen, Jack Lenor, 1955, 1965-1987 (Box 8, Folder 38-40)
    - Liebes, Dorothy, 1969-1988 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Lord and Taylor, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Marble, 1952-1965 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Museum of Decorative Arts of Montreal/American Friends of Canada Committee, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1974-1976 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Museum of Modern Art, 1978, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Natzler, Gertrud and Otto, circa 1949-1964 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Natzler, Gertrud and Otto, 1965-1992, undated (Box 8, Folder 45-46)
    - Pahlmann, William, circa 1952-1982 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1970, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Resources Council, Inc., 1978-1982 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Robsjohn-Gibbings, Terence Harold, 1948-1982, undated (Box 8, Folder 50-51)
    - Seattle World's Fair/American Institute of Interior Designers conference
      - "A Room is Born," April 1962 (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - Conference Material, April 1962 (Box 15, Folder 17)
      - World's Fair Material, April 1962 (Box 15, Folder 18)
      - Miscellaneous, April 1962 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Tafel, Edgar, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - Tiffany Glass, 1955-1958, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - Universities and Colleges, 1950-1958 (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Williamsburg Restoration, Inc., 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Wright, Russel, undated (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Subseries IIIC. Speeches and Publications
    - General, circa 1942-1995 (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - American Institute of Interior Designers speech, November 10 and December 5, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - AID/American Institute of Architects speech, Boston, February 13 1962 (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - AID/AIA speech, Philadelphia, October 30, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - Architectural League speech, April 30 1964 (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Boston Herald Traveler article, January 27 1965 (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - Elsie De Wolfe Award acceptance speech, February 1 1962 (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - Environment article, circa 1960 (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - Everson Memorial Lecture, February-May 1963 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Everyday Art Quarterly article, undated (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - The Fashion Group, Inc. Home Furnishing meeting, October 20 1960 (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - Harper's Magazine panel, circa 1958 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - House Beautiful article, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - Illuminating Engineering Society Annual Conference speech, August 31 1965 (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - Industrial League Forum speech, November 8, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - Interiors article, April 1983 (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - Interiors article, undated (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - Merchandise Mart design panel, June 20 1966 (Box 8, Folder 72)
    - Merchandise Mart press breakfast speech, June 20, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - Merchants and Manufacturers Club Resource Council speech, January 8, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - National Society of Interior Designers/AID meeting, April 19, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 75)
    - New England AID/National Home Fashion League speech, March 15, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 76)
    - New York Times article, September 4, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 77)
    - Progressive Architecture Symposium, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - Retailing Daily article, June 4 1956 (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - Unidentified, 1952-1965, undated (Box 8, Folder 80-82)
    - Miscellaneous unpublished writings, undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Subseries IIID. Design Reference Files
    - Clippings
      - Advertisements (Ad-M) (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Antique architecture (AA) (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Apartments (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Articles (A-M) (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Bath and dressing rooms (B&D-D) (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Bedrooms (Br-D) (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Beds (B) (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Bookcases (Bc) (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Breakfronts (Bf) (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Ceramics (Cer) (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Chairs (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Chests (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - City houses (CiH-A) (Box 9, Folder 8-10)
      - Costume design (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Country houses (CoH-A) (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Details (De-M) (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Dining rooms (DR-D) (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - Displays (Dis-M) (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - Doorways (D-A) (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - Drawings (D-Art) (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - Drawings (D-Art) (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - French architecture (FA) (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - French Modern architecture (FMA) (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - French Modern interiors (FMI) (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Gardens (G-M) (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Glass (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Halls and stairs (H&S-A) (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - International style (IS-A) (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - Le Corbusier (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Living rooms (LR-D) (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - Living rooms (LR-D) (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - Loos, Adolphe (Box 18, Folder 15)
      - Louis XVI (Box 18, Folder 16)
      - L. S. Ayres & Co. (Box 18, Folder 17)
      - Mantels (M-D) (Box 9, Folder 20)
      - Murals (M-Art) (Box 9, Folder 21)
      - Museum pieces (Box 9, Folder 22-23)
      - Museum pieces (Box 18, Folder 18)
      - Nesting furniture (Box 9, Folder 24)
      - Paintings (P-Art) (Box 9, Folder 25-26)
      - Paintings (P-Art) (Box 18, Folder 19)
      - Prints (Pr-Art) (Box 9, Folder 27)
      - Public buildings (PB-A) (Box 18, Folder 20)
      - Radios (Box 18, Folder 21)
      - Reference material for layouts (Box 9, Folder 28)
      - Rugs (R) (Box 9, Folder 29)
      - Scenery (Sce-M) (Box 9, Folder 30)
      - Secretarys (Box 18, Folder 22)
      - Ships and boats (Sh&B-A) (Box 9, Folder 31)
      - Sketches (Sk-M) (Box 9, Folder 32)
      - Sketches (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
      - Sketches (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Stage sets (Box 18, Folder 23)
      - Stores and shops (S&S-A) (Box 9, Folder 33)
      - Surrealism (Box 18, Folder 24)
      - Textiles (Tex) (Box 9, Folder 34)
      - Theatres (Th-A) (Box 9, Folder 35)
      - Town houses (TH-A) (Box 9, Folder 36)
      - Views (V-M) (Box 9, Folder 37)
      - Wallpapers (Wp) (Box 9, Folder 38)
      - Walls and window treatments (Box 18, Folder 25)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Museum Guides and Catalogs
      - B (Box 9, Folder 39-42)
      - C (Box 9, Folder 43-44)
      - C-D (Box 9, Folder 45)
      - F (Box 9, Folder 46)
      - G-H (Box 9, Folder 47)
      - M (Box 9, Folder 48-49)
      - N (Box 9, Folder 50-51)
      - O-P (Box 9, Folder 52)
      - T-V (Box 9, Folder 53)
      - V (Box 9, Folder 54-55)
      - W (Box 9, Folder 56-57)
      - Miscellaneous artists (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous artists (Box 15, Folder 23)
      - Miscellaneous catalogs (Box 10, Folder 2-5)
    - Shaker Furniture Files
      - Brochures on Shaker villages circa 1960-1966 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - News clippings undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Philadelphia Museum exhibit 1962 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Photographs circa 1962-1965 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Subseries IIIE. Miscellaneous
    - Aluminum Company of America; Design Forecast 2, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1942-1983, undated (Box 10, Folder 11-14)
    - News clippings and ephemera, circa 1946-1970 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - News clippings and ephemera, undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
- Series IV. Photographs
  - Subseries IVA. Personal and Family Photographs
    - Crouse Personal Photographs
      - Individual photos, circa 1909-1925, 1929-1968, undated (Box 10, Folder 16-19)
      - Drama Photos
        - University of Georgia productions, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
        - University of Georgia productions-unidentified, undated (Box 10, Folder 21-23)
        - University of Georgia theater and backstage candids, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
        - University of Georgia miscellaneous, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
        - U.S. Army and U.S.O, circa 1942-1945 (Box 10, Folder 26)
        - Headquarters and Service Company, 604th Engineer Camouflage Battalion, July 28, 1943 (Box Mapcase)
      - Family Photos
        - Immediate family, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
        - Extended family, circa 1892-1912 (Box 10, Folder 28)
        - Extended family - Edward S. Cass, undated (Box 10, Folder 29)
      - Friends, including college fraternity and glee club, circa 1918-1967 (Box 10, Folder 30)
      - Friends, including college fraternity and glee club, circa 1928 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Friends, including college fraternity and glee club, circa 1928 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Home, community, and property, undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
      - Military portraits and candids, circa 1942-1945 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Joint Personal Photographs
      - Crouse and Wormley together, undated (Box 10, Folder 33)
      - Home, community, and property, undated (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Wormley Personal Photographs
      - Individual Photos, 1907-1926, 1934-1985, undated (Box 10, Folder 35-39)
      - Family Photos
        - Immediate family, circa 1882-1971, undated (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
        - Immediate family - Edith Wormley, undated (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
        - Immediate family - Edith Wormley and friends, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
        - Immediate family - Myron Wormley in shoe store, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
        - Extended family, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
        - Extended family - cousins, 1906-1915, circa 1918-1947 (Box 11, Folder 7-8)
      - Friends, circa 1926-1980 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Home, community, and property, circa 1939 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Subseries IVB. Travel Photographs
    - Europe, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - South America, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - United States, circa 1931-1940, undated (Box 11, Folder 13-15)
    - West Indies, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 16-24)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 11, Folder 25-32)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Postcards, undated (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Subseries IVC. Miscellaneous Photographs
    - Art and sculpture, undated (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Photographic Christmas cards, undated (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Unidentified persons, undated (Box 11, Folder 36-41)
    - Unidentified persons, undated (Box 12, Folder 1-8)
    - Unidentified persons, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified persons, undated (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 12, Folder 9-10)
    - Negatives (Box 12, Folder 11)